# **Damini Ganesh**

Phone: +1 (312) 813-3883 | Email: daminiganesh07@gmail.com

Linkedin | GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

An enthusiastic, highly adaptable and ambitious graduate with proven IT experience working on Python, Java, HTML, and JavaScript within all three layers of an application.

Excellent communication skills and competent in developing and maintaining interactive web applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Science | Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL Bachelor of Engineering | Visvesvaraya Technological University

Aug 2016 - May 2018

Aug 2012 - June 2016

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### Cove Tool, Atlanta

June 2018 - Present

### Junior Web Developer

- Experienced in all stages of Software Development Life Cycle.
- Developed new features for, cove.tool a web-based application, which aided in a more useful and accurate optimization of results using Django
- Customized the Interface to make it consistent and reduce cognitive load based on direct user feedback and insights from consultants.
- Managed every stage of application development with git version control, virtual servers using AWS EC2 instance and storage and backup using AWS S3
- Implemented UI changes to help users navigate the tool better, provide informative feedback and tested for all possible human errors and updated JS form validation.
- Worked on reducing the number of hits to Postgres database resulting in faster simulations.

### Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago

June 2017 - May 2018

#### JavaScript Developer

- Optimized and refined features to aid the university-wide launch of Planon, a global IWMS software tool.
- Customized the application to make it suitable and efficient for back-end users as well as front-end staff and faculty users.
- Used ES6 and HTML5 to make the user interface clear, concise, consistent, and responsive.

Jan 2017 – April 2017

# **Technical Support Worker**

- Assisted students, faculty, and staff with various technology issues by providing technical support via FootPrints, phone calls, emails, and face-to-face walk-ins.
- Administered troubleshooting and software installation for the Illinois Institute of Technology community.

### **PROJECTS**

### **Enterprise Web Applications**

Developed an e-commerce application using various technologies like JSP, Servlets, etc., which followed the object-oriented design principles and MVC architecture that made it reusable, flexible, and welcoming to iterations.

#### Dealer

Created and implemented a deal scoring game using MERN stack (a cloud-based MongoDB service, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js), component-based architecture, and web pack as a module bundler.

### **Object-Oriented Design Patterns**

Designed and developed a Java Swing application that simulates an animal farm following GOF Design Patterns to provide a general repeatable solution to a commonly occurring problem in software design

### **Software System Architecture**

Designed and implemented a gas pump system using Model-Driven Architecture and design patterns such as state, abstract factory and strategy

# **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Java, Python
- Web Development Technologies/Frameworks: Django, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JSP, Servlets, React.js, WordPress
- Applications: Git, Celery, Eclipse, Microsoft Visual Studio, Apache Tomcat, Atom, Rollbar
- Database: Postgres, MongoDB, MySQL
- Frameworks: MVC, MTV